nibl.com.np 2018-08-31

# Privacy Policy and Grievance Handling

Privacy Policy and Grievance Handling   
  
### **Privacy & Security Policy**

Privacy and Security Policy explains how information may be collected online when you visit this website. Financial and personal information handling requires trust and the Bank respects customer privacy and takes strong action to safeguard all information, including customer’s online sessions. Customer information means personally identifiable information about a customer.

**Objective**

The privacy of visitors to Nepal Investment Bank Ltd. (NIBL)’s site is of the utmost importance. Since NIBL’s website gathers certain types of information about the users of the website and services visitors need to fully understand the purpose of capturing and use of the information. This privacy statement discloses what information NIBL may gather and how it is used. All visitors who visit the site http://www.nibl.com.np and provide information to NIBL online are covered under this Policy

**Privacy Statement**

NIBL does not capture or store any personal information about individuals who access this website. You may voluntarily choose to pass personal details via e-mail whilst making enquiries or forwarding information in response to information available on the website. In these later cases, this personal information is used exclusively by NIBL. NIBL will not pass any of your personal data to outside organizations and/or individuals, except with your express consent. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed as being 100% secure. NIBL cannot ensure or warrant the security of your transmission to us, you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information we make every best effort to ensure its security within our systems.

**Legal Disclaimer**

NIBL makes every effort to ensure that the information provided on its website is accurate. You may download materials displayed on the site for noncommercial, personal use only, provided you also retain all copyright and other proprietary notices contained on the materials. You may not, however, distribute, modify, transmit, reuse, report, or use the contents of the website for public or commercial purposes, including the text, images, audio, and video without NIBL’s written permission.

NIBL cannot guarantee this, and accepts no liability for any information or advice given via its website. The information contained within this website does not constitute legal advice. Those seeking specific financial advice or have personal account queries should contact their nearest Branch.

**Personal Information**

NIBL may collect personally identifiable information, like names, postal addresses, email addresses, etc., when voluntarily submitted by visitors. NIBL uses these information to improve the visitor’s experience on the site and make subsequent offers to the visitor on products, which may be of interest. Additionally, when you visit our website, NIBL may collect the following information in order to service your accounts, save you time and money, and better respond to your needs.

• Application information. Information that you provide to us on forms, via the Internet or otherwise.

• Transaction and experience information. Information about your online transactions and account experience, as well as information about our online communication with you.

**Protecting Customer information from external entities**

NIBL may use and share the information provided by the customers with its affiliates and third parties for providing services and any service-related back-office activities. However, such affiliates and third parties shall be required to strictly agree to use the information obtained from NIBL only for specified purposes.

NIBL may share the collected information to conform to legal requirements or to comply with legal process and regulations. The information provided to affiliates, third parties/external organizations should not be used for marketing purposes. NIBL does not sell or share any customer information with entities outside NIBL who may want to offer you their own product and services.

**Email**

NIBL collects and keeps the contents of email you send us in addition to your contact address and NIBL’s response. This enables us to respond to your request and questions. Emails sent to NIBL should be used for inquiries that are not sensitive or confidential as regular, non-encrypted Internet email. If NIBL needs information beyond your name, address, email address and telephone number, we will contact you personally. NIBL will not request that you confirm your Personal ID, account numbers, password or other sensitive information via email.

**Cookies & Browsers **

Bank’s site may use cookies depending on the features offered. Cookies are small data files that a website stores on visitor’s computer. Cookies store non-personal information like browser, ISP, OS etc. Cookies can also help customize the Site for visitors. Personal information like name, customer-id, account no. and contact number etc. cannot be collected via cookies.

**Commitment to Data Security**

NIBL employs a range of technologies and processes to protect the information maintained on our systems from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

**Hypertext Links and Viruses**

It is expressly reminded that NIBL has no control or liability regarding the creation of links to other sites external to NIBL and regarding the content of said sites. Therefore, you accept that your choice to access another site through a hypertext link is made under your own responsibility. Accordingly, any direct or indirect bias resulting from your access to another site connected by a hypertext link may not incur NIBL liability.

You must take the necessary precautions to ensure that the site you have chosen does not contain any virus or any other destructive elements. NIBL may in no way be held responsible for direct or indirect damages resulting from the use of its site or other sites related to it.

**Procedure for the Processing of Job Contacts**

If a person responds to a job listing contained on NIBL’s website, this does not guarantee that NIBL will proceed with that candidate's contact, even if the candidate corresponds to the profile of the position being offered. NIBL will contact candidates whose inquiries have been accepted in order to arrange for the person to meet the NIBL personnel responsible for his/her recruitment. A candidate will only be deemed definitively to have been recruited once all of the recruitment procedures set out in NIBL internal recruitment policies have been complied with.

Please note that although NIBL website is regularly updated, and it is not possible to guarantee that each position appearing thereon is still available. Please also note that no contractual relationship will be created between the applicant and NIBL as a result either of the applicant sending his or her application to NIBL or, unless otherwise specifically indicated by NIBL, of any subsequent exchange of correspondence, whether by electronic or regular means, between the applicant and NIBL. NIBL excludes all liability for positions no longer being available or employment applications not being accepted.

**Responses to Employment Contacts**

Responses to employment contacts, whether spontaneous or not, will be sent to the electronic address indicated by the applicant. If the applicant does not give an electronic address, responses to applications will be sent by regular mail to the address of the person making the contact. The person making the contact assumes full responsibility for any electronic address provided to NIBL to enable it to send its response to the employee's contact form. NIBL excludes all liability for the confidentiality of the address indicated in the application in particular, a professional electronic address, not being maintained, thereby enabling third parties to learn of NIBL response.

## **Grievance Handling and Dispute Resolution**

Customers should check the receipt provided after each Electronic Transactions. Transactions will be termed valid only if it exists in the Core Banking System and the same will be reflected in the receipt. The Bank will correct any errors immediately as soon as it comes to the Bank’s notice. If required the customer will be informed after making necessary amendments.

All forms of grievances would be handled done through Customer Service Department (CSD). The Bank would place trained CSD staff able to resolve most customer issues.  Unresolved issues would be escalated to IT or relevant departments. It is the responsibility of the concerned department to resolve the issues and communicate the same to either the Customer or Customer Service Department.

However, mistakes could occur from the customer side in which the following will be adhered to,

I. For cases when the customers transfer funds to a wrong account (destination account), the dispute resolution would start after the customer provides a written request to the Bank (Customer Service Department). The Bank may as per the circumstance hold the funds from the destination account until the case is resolved. The Bank before reversing the transaction will take written consent from the account holder of the destination account.

II. For cases when the customer does not receive service or products even after successful transaction (transaction present in the Core Banking System), they can contact Customer Service and report the problem. The Bank may as per the circumstance hold the funds from the accounts in question until the case is resolved. The Bank would act as a mediator in these cases to resolve the issue between the merchant and the customer.

The Bank is committed to providing a high level of service. However there may be occasions when complaints and disputes arise. In such instances, the Code of Customer Service specifies a structured process (below) for the complaint to be dealt with.

**A. Principles**

The underlying principles for dealing with the complaints are:

• Sincerity – Customer’s complaint is an important feedback and the bank will treat it seriously

• Transparency - The procedures for handling complaints are documented and apply to all customers

• Effectiveness - The procedures will provide for a speedy resolution

**B. Raising a Complaint - with the Bank**

If the customer has an issue to raise or is dissatisfied with a particular service with the bank, there are 3 steps that can be taken:

**Step One**

Contact the Bank by:

• Approaching the Bank’s branch staff (Customer Service Department), or

• E-mailing the Bank using the “Contact Us” option found in the website or at [info@nibl.com.np](mailto:info@nibl.com.np), or

• Filling up the eBanking feedback form available in the eBanking login page, or

• Writing to the Bank

Customer are required to provide the Bank with details of the specific complaint/ dispute and any supporting documents to help expedite the investigation.

On its part, Bank will ensure that:

i. All staff who deal directly with customers are familiar with the complaint procedures and are able to help you by giving correct information about these procedures,

ii. Customer’s complaint is acknowledged within 2 business days of receipt of it, and

iii. Customer’s complaint is investigated and the customer is informed of the investigation status within 14 business days of receipt of the complaint

**Step Two**

If the customer is dissatisfied with the outcome, the customer may contact the Bank at:

Nepal Investment Bank Ltd.

Durbar Marg, Kathmandu,

Nepal.

PO Box: 3412

Telephone: +977-1-4228229, 4242530

Fax : +977-1-4226349, 4228927

Email: [csd@nibl.com.np](mailto:csd@nibl.com.np)

Officers empowered to objectively handle Customer’s complaint would:

i. Give customer a response within 14 business days of the appeal.

ii. Inform customer of any further action can be taken including going to a third party.

**Step Three**

If Customer is still dissatisfied with Bank’s response, after dealing as stated above the customers can approach the Retail Head at the following address:

Nepal Investment Bank Ltd.

Durbar Marg, Kathmandu,

Nepal.

Telephone: +977-1-4228229, 4242530

Fax : +977-1-4226349, 4228927

Where possible, the Retail Head will give the customer an assessment of the case and mediate to resolve the dispute. If necessary, the customer will need to authorize the bank to disclose the customer’s account information to the parties who are involved in the investigation. The Retail Head will refer the case to the Bank’s relative department if it has not yet had a chance to look into the complaint, or if necessary escalate the case to management.
